Ian McFarland

Senior Application Developer

E: iwmcfarland@gmail.com P: 206-930-7046 L: Clawson, MI, USA

Summary

Senior software developer with 10+ years experience in web application development, systems integration and automating tasks. Proficient in working with users, whether co-workers or clients, to define requirements and build new functionality. Many successful iterations through the entire project and software development life cycle in the revenue and telecommunications fields.

Key Skills

- C# NET development
- SQL development / TSQL

- SDLC from design to production
- Data exchange between systems

Technical

Languages: C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python

Platforms/Libraries: .NET Core/Framework, Hangfire, Topshelf, Dapper; Mulesoft; Angular; SQL Server/TSQL

Tools: Jenkins CI/CD, Gitlab

Professional Experience

TELNET WORLDWIDE, Madison Heights, MI, 2014 – Present Senior Application Developer

- Implemented and maintained web based portal application used by TelNet customers, sales agents and internal employees
- Built APIs with .NET Core and Mulesoft platforms which automated provisioning tasks and integration with third-party services
- Developed E-911, Caller ID data management APIs to enable customer self-service data management
- Integrated back office support systems with new Salesforce implementation
- Supported junior developers and contractors on various projects
- Created CI/CD jobs for API deployment in Jenkins

Ian McFarland

Senior Application Developer

E: iwmcfarland@gmail.com P: 206-930-7046 L: Clawson, MI, USA

Professional History (Continued)

REVENUE SOLUTIONS INC, Pembroke, MA, 2007 – 2014 Senior Consultant/Developer

- Developed services, web pages (ASP.NET), offline processes, and SQL Server stored procedures as part of a full integrated tax system development project.
- Lead design and implementation of user security roles for revenue agency personnel; over
 150 users in 20 different access roles.
- Lead design of dynamic data elements for generating over 50 notices sent to taxpayers and other state agencies.
- Implemented case management system, including SQL data mining and refresh process, for the Individual Income Tax collections team for the state of Rhode Island.
- Lead client meetings to gather requirements and define gaps in support of case management and integrated tax system implementations in multiple state revenue agencies.
- Conducted user training sessions in support of collections process enhancement project.

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON, Seattle, WA, 2002 - 2007

Research Scientist/Engineer – Department of Genome Sciences (2004-2007)

- Performed analysis on DNA sequence data in support of single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) discovery research project.
- Contributed completed SNP data for over 50 genes to the National Institute of Health.
- Performed troubleshooting and maintenance on PostgreSQL databases storing genetic analysis data as well as Perl scripts used in analysis process.
- Platform/Technologies: Red Hat Linux, Perl and Bash scripting, PostgreSQL database

Analysis Technician – School of Fisheries (2002-2004)

- As part of a behavioral ecology project undertaken by the School of Fisheries, analyzed video and image data to record the schooling behavior of fish.
- Translated hours of video into positional data and pathing information.
- Tested and provided troubleshooting of custom path-finding software.
- Platform/Technologies: MATLAB, Perl scripting, SAS statistical analysis

Education

Bachelor of Science in Biology, 2002 – University of Washington – Seattle, WA **Post-Baccalaureate studies in Computer Science**, 2003-2004 – University of Washington – Seattle, WA